If you have a zero balance account in State Bank of India, then do
you know
that all the zero balance
account holders are
receiving such messages from the bank in which it is written
PM JGB BY or PM SB BY
policy is due for renewal, that is,
an insurance policy has been added to your account by the bank, the
premium amount of which is going to be
deducted from your bank account.
In this message, you are also being told that
before 28 April 2026, you have to
save money in your bank account
so that your premium can be deducted on time.  So if
you still do not know about it that
what is PM SB and what is PM JJB scheme
which is applicable on your account and
why the bank is going to deduct this money from your bank account
and how much money will be deducted.  You are going to get
complete information about this in today's video.
So if you have
a zero balance account in State Bank of India
or anyone in your family has one, then
definitely watch this video completely so that
you do not suffer any loss.  So first of all let us
talk about PM SBY scheme.
If you have received this type of message, then
it is very important for you to know for
what premium the bank is going to deduct from your bank account.
So let me tell you
that PM SBI i.e. Pradhan Mantri
Suraksha Bima Yojana is an accidental
scheme whose premium for one year is only ₹20.
If this scheme is
linked to your bank account, then ₹20 gets
auto-renewed from your account every year.
Now let us talk about what you actually get from the government in
exchange for this ₹20 under the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana
?  Look, this is an accidental
insurance.  So in this
you get an accidental insurance policy from the government.
Under this, if any insured
person meets with an accident
due to which he dies, then
in return, your family is
given an assistance amount of ₹ lakh from the government to help your family.
If the insured
meets with an accident due to which one of his hands, one leg, one
eye or any other part of the body
stops working, then in such a case, the insured is
given an amount of ₹1 lakh by the government.  The government had launched such schemes
for people belonging to poor families
so that they could secure their lives.
So, if
you have received this message from the bank on your mobile number that
PM SB Buy policy is due for renewal,
then there is no need to worry at all.
Only an amount of ₹20 will be deducted from your account
so that this policy can be
continued further.  If you have
received a message on your number
saying PM JJB by policy is
due for renewal, it means that
Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima
Yojana is applicable on your account.  This is also a government
scheme whose one year premium is ₹436.
In this also, if the policyholder
dies due to any reason, then the
family
gets assistance amount of ₹ lakh from the government.
Now in this, there was the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima
Yojana i.e. PMSBY scheme in
which a premium of ₹20 is deducted.  This is the difference between this and the
Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti
Bima Yojana.  Firstly, there
is the difference in premium.  A premium of ₹436
is deducted in this scheme and only ₹20 is deducted in PM SBY
i.e. Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana.
This
is an accidental insurance.  In this, if
any accident happens to the insured, only then the
family
gets help.  But if we
talk about Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana which is PM JBY
Scheme.  A premium of ₹436 is deducted in this.
In return, even if you meet with an accident,
your family will get a sum of ₹2 lakh
and if you die a natural death,
if any policyholder dies a natural death, then on
that too, the family members are
given a sum of ₹1 lakh.  So if you have also
received both these messages,
then very soon the
bank is going to deduct the amount of ₹20 and ₹436 from your account.
Now look, a question must be arising in your mind
that you have
not applied this scheme on your account, then how has
this scheme been implemented on your account and
why is this message coming from your bank account without your
knowledge and why is
this money going to be deducted from your bank account without your permission, then let
me tell you that if you have an account in State Bank of
India, especially a zero
balance account, then
you must have opened the zero balance account at the CSP point of State Bank of India,
where all the
CSP holders
get the target from the bank that they have to implement
Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana and
Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana on all the accounts opened with them.
Whether you
like it or not.  But if I
talk about these two insurance policies then
it is absolutely correct.  You should take them and continue taking
them.  Because the
facilities that you are getting from the government for such a low amount of money, the security that is being provided to your life, the
talk of financially supporting your family
, you will not get to see this anywhere else for such a
low amount of money.
Because if any accident happens to the insured, then
no one will come forward to support your family.  If you have taken both these
schemes, then
your family can receive at least ₹4 lakh from the government.
So if you did
not know about them till now then
you have got the information.  I hope
that the
information I have shared with you in today's video will be useful.  I
hope you liked it very much.  You must have understood very well
what is Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana?
And what is Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana
?  And if you still want to stop them, then
I will tell you an easy way to stop them.  If you do
not want to keep these schemes active in your account, then
you should not keep any money deposited in your bank account till 31st May.
As soon as the
premium payment period for these policies is
over, both these
policies will be automatically closed from your account.  And if
you want, you can also close both these policies by going to the bank.
So for now, that's all for today's
video. We will meet you
in another video with new information,
a new update and with new enthusiasm. Till then,
Jai.